All right, let's make a get request from
our browser. And you may be thinking,
are you sure I'm ready for that? I don't
even know how to make a get request. Um,
I guarantee you, you're ready for it.
You make get requests all the time. So,
if I come up here to the URL bar, URL
stands for uniform resource locator. In
other words, it's just an address that
makes it really easy for us to find
resources. So, if I come up here and I
type www.google.com
and I hit enter, it gives me back a web
page. Congratulations, you've made a get
request. You requested the Google web
page and Google returned it. So, you
said, "Can you please get me the Google
web page?" When you make requests, um
all sorts of information um can be sent
on that request. For example, sometimes
when you fill a form out, um that form
will send out to a server. So, I could
say, "What is a get request?" And if I
hit enter, I actually sent a whole bunch
of information in a request out to
Google. Um, and you can actually see all
of the information that I sent out. And
that was sent out using a get request.
And so I sent out the words my query was
what is a get request? And then
this is all of the other data that got
sent with it that they were using to
customize the search results for me. um
as far as um what answer I am most
likely to want. And here I can see um
posted answers. Well, if you want to
work um with um if you want to get
external data, one of the ways you do
that is using something called a REST
API. A REST API uses get, put, post, and
delete to work with your code. And if
you'll give me a second, I'm going to
pause this video and go grab the URL. I
forgot the URL for the API I was going
to show you. So, give me one second.
Okay, I've got that URL. So, let's make
a request to an API. This API is an
advice API. It gives you back advice.
Disclaimer, I did not write this API.
Um, I have no idea what advice it's
going to give back. I do not necessarily
endorse the advice that it's going to
give. It might be good advice, it might
be bad advice. it's just advice. So, um,
we're going to go to an advice API. To
do that, up here on the URL bar, I'm
going to type HTTPS.
That means I am going to be making an
HTTP
um, request, and I want it to be secure.
So, HTTPS and then I'm going to do
double slash then I'm going to say
API.lip.comvice.
And so this is a URL
um for the API. And when I type it in,
it's going to go find that API and it's
going to make a get request. When I hit
enter,
I got back information. It wasn't a web
page. When I type in ww.google.com,
that gives me back a web page. But what
this gave me back is it gave me back an
object. In fact, it gave me back a
JavaScript object. And if it's a
JavaScript object, I can then access
parts of that object. And that is how
you can get it into your code. So, um I
actually do like this piece of advice.